Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Some people say, "Why care?"
They feel like it's a losing battle in these neighborhoods.
And my response is, "Why not care?
If we don't do something, nothing will change!"
It's like T.B. Joshua says, "The reason why we do good is to change the bad that we see".
So these youth that we're reaching with absentee parents,
if they weren't being reached, these are the same ones that we'll be doing home invasions.
These are the same ones that will be school shooters, shooting up our schools.
These are the same ones that will be committing homicide.
And what else would you expect?
Living in hostile, drug infested environments, with no guidance.
It's a recipe for destruction.
So without great people like T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV partners and their support,
it's no doubt that these youths would be lost.
Because many of them already feel like, if my parents don't care, then who cares?
They feel like, if my parents don't want me, then who wants me?
And since everyone has a part to play, our part is to use every good thing
to reroute them from the drugs,
to reroute them from the crime,
to reroute them from these destructive paths.
The avenues and the tools that we use to do this is mentoring, being big brothers to them.
Many of them like sports. So we use basketball.
When we coach them and train them,
we teach them integrity, we teach them character,
we teach them identity, we teach on right choices,
we also teach them principles from T.B. Joshua's book ''The Mirror' -
the principles we teach them, showing them who they were,
who they are and who they shall be.
And now, they can no longer just apply it on the court,
but they can apply it off the court, in real life also.
STRAIGHT OUTTA Emmanuel TV
I was born and raised in Defiance, Ohio.
When I was 3, my father died in a semi accident.
He was hit by a semi truck, coming home from work one night.
After that, there was a lot of hardship and a lot of struggle.
There were days we didn't have food; we didn't know if we were going to eat or not.
In 4th grade, the teachers told my mum that I was too hyper and that I needed to be on medication.
So then I was put on medication.
As the years went on, even though I was taking medication, I was still depressed.
I started drinking.
I started doing drugs.
And then fast forward, after college,
a few months after I graduated, I tried to take my life.
I took a bottle and a half of pills.
One night, I was just feeling so low, so broken.
My girlfriend at the time had just broken up with me.
I had just lost my job. I was just feeling so low.
I just felt like there was no reason for me to be alive.
So I took a bottle and a half of pills and drank a bunch of alcohol.
Then I drove to my friend's house.
I don't even remember driving there.
It was a miracle that I even made it to my friend's house.
But in the middle of the night, I woke up and remembered that I had taken those pills
and I tried to stand up, go to the bathroom and try to throw the pills up.
But my legs were numb from all the effects of the medication.
I couldn't stand up so I had to crawl to the bathroom.
When I got to the bathroom, I tried to throw the pills up and that's the last thing I remember.
I blacked out and went into a seizure.
The next thing I know is that I woke up in the emergency room, and I literally thought it was a dream.
After I got out of the hospital, things were still...
I was still drinking, I was still depressed.
Then I met an evangelist from The SCOAN
and she gave me a bottle of the New Morning Water by Prophet T.B. Joshua.
When I got home, I began to administer it to myself,
began to apply it to myself every day,
believing in God for healing, believing in God for deliverance.
And I got that healing. A couple of months later, I was able to throw the pills completely out.
It's been almost six years now that I've taken medication.
I feel free. I feel good.
I used to be depressed, I used to be suicidal.
Now I work full-time for the Emmanuel TV USA team.
We work with all kinds of kids that grow up in hardship, just like I did.
We feed the homeless, we help the elderly, we do all kinds of great things.
I am just so thankful and grateful that God used Prophet T.B. Joshua
to bring the New Morning Water into my life and healed me and delivered me.
If God can do it for me, He can do it for you.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
I used to think, it was so hard to reach kids.
But I found out something - love is the key.
Just like T.B. Joshua says," Let love lead".
And that's what we are doing - we are going into these neighborhoods, we feed them,
we give them Emmanuel TV backpacks and build relationships with them.
We are even developing Emmanuel TV basketball teams.
Giving them a way out - away from the drugs and the crime.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Okay.
Hey, you are good. You need to make an advance, son. You need to be going inside some time.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Good shot.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
HAMILTON, OHIO
THE EMMANUEL TV OFFICE USA
So it's 1:30 am, and we're here, at the Emmanuel TV office in the USA.
Chris, what's the inventory on the shoes?
Okay, according to the list, we have 125 pairs for the guys and the girls.
The Emmanuel TV team is arranging, they're preparing to load in
because we have to drive three and a half to four hours away to the Gibault Children Facility in Indiana.
And we have so many items that we're taking for them there.
We're taking shoes, pants and shorts.
We have shoes for them as well.
For the young ladies, we have dresses.
We have a whole load of shirts.
We have hats.
We have glasses.
We have a whole load of hygiene products for them,
as well as we do at Emmanuel TV resource office.
The reason why we're doing this is to change their lives.
Many of them are, as we said before, they're from ages 6,
some of them are in their teens.
However, unless something changes,
they will be there in this facility until they're 21 years of age.
So remember, many of them don't have any involvement with family
and so we're doing this so that we might be their family,
so that we can be an extension of their families and just be there for them.
We've got to remember like T.B. Joshua says, "In a world that cares less,
we have to care more and everyone has something to give".
Everyone can do something.
Everyone - even if it's a smile, you may just loan someone your strength who's weaker than you.
All of us has something to give.
We're looking forward to having a great event
and we're going to carry you along.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
INDIANAPOLIS, IN
It's always good to have a team.
Even if it's a small team.
Because no one can do it alone!
Especially when driving is involved, this late at night or early morning.
Multiple vehicles going from one state to another state, four hours away.
Having a team is great because one can drive while the other rests
and you always got to factor in natural challenges.
And so for us driving from Ohio to Indiana and the Gibault Children Facility,
our challenge was the weather, because of the season - transitioning from winter to spring.
So it was a lot of rain.
However, we stayed the course.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
TERRA HAUTE, IN
One reason why we're doing this charity event today
is because of what took place the last time we were at the Gibault Facility.
If you find something that you do very well, it's an indication of who you are.
What about you?
When I was in my other school, I used to go around to other classrooms with my teacher
and help other kids solve problems.
Wow, we can already tell you are a leader.
Right?
The first thing that you said you love to do is help people with their what?
Problems.
Helping them with their problems. Wow, that's amazing.
So can you tell me, because I can look
and tell by the things that you're saying what type of person you are.
So who are you?
I'm a leader.
You're leader. Definitely, you're a leader.
I'm an encourager.
Yes.
I want to be a therapist.
There you go.
And as I spoke with these youths, even though many were medicated and had issues,
when I spoke with them, I realized this: They had a lot of potential.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
GIBAULT FACILITIES
INDIANA, USA
One of the directors was giving us a tour and we came across one of the students in the hallway,
who was just too hyper to be in class at the moment
and the director told us that the student is normally very violent.
But when we approached him,
he just wanted to talk about music and he was very respectful.
I think Tupac is still alive, you know that?
And I can go on for weeks. I've got a lot of research on Tupac.
You do?
Yeah.
Hey Logan, let them do what they need to do.
They are doing what they got to do.
- Logan, how old are you?
- Huh?
- How old are you?
- I'm 16.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
- How are you?
- Hi, I'm Diane. How are you?
Good, good.
And the interesting thing about it is, he's one of the smartest students in the whole campus.
He's one of my favourite kids, too.
He can't just get it together sometimes.
(Inaudible)
He's actually one of the smartest students we have.
All these kids need is family.
They need somebody that cares to be in their lives.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
First of all, I would like to say that the Gibault Children Facility is doing a great job.
They're doing a tremendous job, but it doesn't stop there.
It's going to take other organizations and other people to help raise these youth
and that's why I'm glad that Emmanuel TV is a part of that in raising these youth.
Because even though Gibault is doing a great job,
it's still evident that these youths are hurt and many of them are traumatized in many ways.
There is a reason why we are here.
There is a reason why we are breathing.
- Do you know what it is?
- No.
Ok, what about you?
Supposedly, God gave us a reason to be here. I don't know why.
Let me tell you something. Yes, for each and everyone of us.
I mea,n I went through a lot hurt in my life, so technically I don't think I should be alive.
Plus, my real mum called me a "Walking A**hole" because I was a walking A**hole.
Ok, I hear what you're saying, but understand this right here.
There is something good about you and there is a purpose for everything.
There is a purpose for an apple, what is that?
For you to eat an apple.
Exactly, there's something great about you, there's something on the inside of you that is unique,
that is different from everybody else.
Also understand this right here:
A lot of times, when we are lost in life, it's simply because we don't know the address for our future.
A lot of times, if we don't understand the greatness that's within us,
each and every one of us has something to contribute to society.
Regardless of what you have been through, regardless of what you're going through.
There's something great about each and every one of you.
There's something unique about each and every one of you.
If they're traumatized in many ways, it's going to play out in their lives,
and that's what's happening and many of them get their identity from the music,
from media and so forth, especially with not having that family involvement.
But we've got to be able to continue to reach them on whatever level and communicate with them
and make them feel important in society.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
So as we were doing this charity event, the local news got wind of it and they came out and covered it.
And just like many other people when they see the great things going on, "Wow, this is great!
Who are you?" And like I often tell people, "I am just an extra set of hands and extra set of feet
that is on the ground to help get the resources to people".
But it's not really me. I'm not the one that's really doing it.
It really comes from T.B. Joshua.
It really comes from the Emanuel TV partners.
Don't just stand by and watch.
The generation of today goes by the waste side.
We can change the bad that we see by doing good.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
They're just amazed by everything that's going on and see we come from a time where
America used to go all over the world and take resources and relief
and now America is in need and the roles have change.
Now, you have great humanitarians like T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV
come in and send in the resources so that we can get to the need to the people.
He's someone that believes that distance isn't a barrier, that regardless of where you are,
we should be able to get the needs to the people.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
So, even though it is different and roles have changed - that's the truth.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
EMMANUEL TV RESOURCE ROOM
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
During our visit at the Gibault Children's Home,
we came across a classroom with nothing but little children
and I thought to myself I can't imagine being six years old with no parents around.
trying to figure out life on my own.
That's why it's such a blessing that T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV partners,
all across the world, are providing resources so that we can bless these kids.
Everything that's been done, everything that's been provided
is making a change and making a difference in these kids' lives.
- Hi, how are you?
- I love the Pacers.
- You love the Pacers?
- Yeah.
- There we go.
- You're like a little engineer over here, you like making airplanes?
- High five.
- High five, man!
- Snail, I mean turkey.
- Snail!
- Do you want to see how many airplanes I have?
- Sure.
- I made them all.
- Wow, you did?
- Yeah.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
- How are you doing? Are you doing good?
- That's good.
- Are you reading?
- Yes.
- Good. What's your name?
- My name is Antonio.
- Antonio?
- Yes.
- Nice to meet you, Antonio.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
The director gave us a tour of some of the dorm rooms
and as you can see, some of the rooms only had one bed.
Those rooms with one bed are for those students that tend to be violent.
A lot of them are violent because that's the only way they know how to deal with their problems.
And those rooms with two beds, well, they are able to get along with their fellow students.
We also ran into this kid that occupied a room with one bed.
He was known to be a violent guy.
But once again, we're talking with him in reference to his dream.
He relayed to us that his dream is to be a pilot in the Air Force.
We began going through these classrooms and interacting with the children.
I noticed that a lot of these young ladies were brilliant in their own right!
But because of the lack of family involvement, many of them were medicated,
just to cope with life and that was me.
I used to be heavily medicated, just to deal with one day to the next.
But now, it's such a blessing to be able to work with Emmanuel TV
and just change the lives of these kids.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
- So, what book are you reading?
- I am reading "Chicken Soup for the Teenage Soul''.
''Class Piggy Bank'' is where I just started.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Like TB Joshua says, "Your dream is a photograph of your future
and when your purpose is clear, your life will have meaning".
So this is the message that we are spreading to all of these youths.
We have got a Veterinarian here.
Hi guys!
As you can see, the Emmanuel TV team has prepared a pizza party at the youths' request.
Previously, we were preparing a dinner for hundred youth,
but when we arrived for the charity event, to our surprise, Gibault had gained 45 more youth
and the majority of youth asked if we could have a pizza party instead.
So, we ordered pizza, salad and soda from the best pizza restaurant in town.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Let me be known by love
I need love to help
To help and be helped
Let me be known by love
I need love to give
To give and receive
Let me be known by love
I need love to live
To live for eternity
Sons and daughters of love
By love
Let us act love
Let us do love
By love
Following the light of love
Love
Transmission of love
Help those in need
Love
Let love lead
Let the people say, 'Yeah!'
Let me be known by love
I need love to worship
To worship my Saviour
Let me be known by love
I need love to pray
To pray to my Father
Let me be known by love
I need love to live
To live for eternity
Love does not kill
By love
Love does not fear
Love does not destroy
By love
Love does not keep malice
Nor envy or jealous
By love
Look right, not arrogant
Let love lead
Let the people say, 'Yeah!'
Let me be known by love
I need love to dance
To dance for His glory
Let me be known by love
We need love to live
To live as a nation
Let me be known by love
I need love to live
To live for eternity
When no love, there's war
By love
When no love, there's fighting
When no love, division
By love
When no love, corruption
When no love, discrimination
By love
When no love, no peace
Let love lead
Let the people say, 'Yeah!'
It's such a blessing that T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV partners all across the world
are providing resources so that we can bless these kids and change their lives
because some of the looks on these kids' faces when we came in and gave them shoes and everything
some of them said, "I've never had anyone do anything like this for me before".
To our surprise, many of the staff at Gibault and even a local police officer
joined the Emmanuel TV team in giving out shoes.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Oh my God! Oh wow!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Here you go, these are for you.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
I can't believe that these are mine.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Thank you, Emmanuel TV!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Thank you, Emmanuel TV! I will always appreciate this.
Thanks, man!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Look at mine!
Ooh, we got on the same shoes!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Thank you, Emmanuel TV!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Thank you, Emmanuel TV!
I love this stuff.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Aw, look at this!
Oh, wait, no, thank you. Aw man! I missed it.
I like it.
I know, right?
Do you like mine?
Do you like it?
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
(Screams in excitement)
Shoes, we got shoes!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
- Thank you!
- You're welcome!
- Thank you, guys!
- You're very welcome.
Can I say something to the camera real quick?
Thank you Emmanuel TV!
It is my first time that I have Jordans. I cried because I never had Jordans in my life.
It's awesome! Thank you so much.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
- Aw, these are Uggs, oh my God!
- I wanna see.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Here you go.
Thank you!
You're welcome!
Thank you, guys!
You're very welcome!
Can I say something to the camera really quick?
Thank you, Emmanuel TV!
Good job!
It's the first time I have Jordans. I cried because I never had Jordans in my life.
It's awesome. Thank you very much!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
- Aw, these are Uggs, oh my God!
- I wanna see.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Here you go.
Thank you!
Oh! It is such a cute black boot!
Those are perfect for you!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Don't forget to say thank you, ladies!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Here you go!
Thank you!
Oh! It is such a cute black boot!
Those are perfect for you!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Don't forget to say thank you, ladies!
(Everyone)
Thank you!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
That's for you.
Don't forget to get some glasses too.
There are also t-shirts for you too.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Thank you!
You are welcome.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
I like those. Thank you!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Look at these! What!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
I love it!
Diva!
Thank you!
"Diva in training" - is that what it says?
Yeah.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Sweet, thank you!
You're welcome!
Thank you so much. I am very grateful.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Dude, this is sweet!
Thank you!
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
I think it's great. I think there's a need in young people,
especially those who aren't given their needs as young kids.
Gibault is a place where they can have those needs fulfilled
and we have outside people come in, outside influences.
That only makes people stronger and better.
That's what these young people need at this age.
Your very experience - just tell us your position and stuff.
I'm a police officer. I'm the spokesperson for the police department.
I travel with groups and speak to groups all the time.
I see it - there is a need.
It takes a certain person to fulfill that need because not everybody can do it.
It is not an easy job to do but it's important so we are thankful for people willing to do it.
Keith.
I would first like to thank you for coming all the way from Cincinnati, Ohio.
I know you guys are all around the world but to take the time to come to Terre Haute, Indiana
and to work with our children in...
We don't realize how important it is for kids in a residential treatment facility
to have someone come to their house.
This is their house; they don't get to go home. They are here 24/7.
So for someone to come to their house and bring them gifts like this...
As a parent, I am always taking things home to my kids.
You guys are basically an extension of our family and we appreciate it
because it takes a community to really raise a kid.
You are a part of our community now, We appreciate all you have done.
Thank you all.
Transforming America's Youth
Emmanuel TV Team USA
Exactly what they said.
It's a great thing to see these kids with smiles on their faces
as they open up something they know they couldn't have where they were coming from.
They have to stay here 365 days, 7 days a week.
Where they were coming from, they know they were not privileged enough to have
Jordans, Uggs, hats, tabogans or anything else like that so you all are...
We cannot express how much we like you guys and how much we want you guys to be part of our family.
Thank you for all of your help.
Emmanuel TV - thank you!
TT: Esther Mwelwa,13/08/18
RV: Mel Flowers 19/08/2018